So far you have learned some tricks to implement
迄今为止 你已经学会了一些技巧
the particle filter and how to assess
知道了如何部署粒子滤波器 以及如何评估
the accuracy of your filter.
滤波器的准确性
Now I'll give you an overview of the code
下面 我们一起看一下
that you'll be using to complete your project.
完成实战项目使用的代码
Let's first look at the file main.cvp.
首先 我们来看 main.cvp 这个文件
This file will run your particle filter
这个文件会运行你的粒子滤波器
as well as measure its runtime and calculate
测量其运行时间 然后在每个步骤
the weighted error at each time step.
计算加权误差
The first thing you'll need to do
你要做的第一件事
is set the number of particles in your filter
就是在滤波器中的 To Do 注释下
under this To Do comment.
设置粒子数量
M is the number of particles to draw.
M 代表粒子数量
Here I have set the uncertainties
这里 我已经设置了你要使用的
for the different measurements that you'll be using.
不同测量值的不确定性
Next the main function reads in the math data, the control
接下来 main 函数读入每个步骤的
data, and the observation data for each time step.
数学数据、控制数据和观察数据
In this for loop, you'll implement
在这个 for 循环中 你需要在这个 To Do 注释下
one step of your particle filter under this To Do comment here.
实现粒子滤波器的一个步骤
At the end of each time step, you
在每个时间步结束时
will calculate and print out the weighted error.
你需要计算并打印出加权误差
Finally, after your particle filter
最后 粒子滤波器
has gone through the entire driving sequence,
经历整个驾驶流程后
the main function will calculate the runtime for your filter,
Main 函数会计算你的滤波器的运行时间
and that's it for main.cvp.
这就是 main.cvp 文件的功能
You will implement most of the particle filter code
大多数粒子滤波器代码的实现
in particlefilter.cvp.
都在 particlefilter.cvp 文件中
This file contains all of the implementations
这个文件包括了粒子滤波器类不同函数的
of the functions of the particle filter class.
所有实现
Now we'll go over each function you'll
现在 我们来看一下完成这个项目
have to complete to finish the project.
所需要的每一个函数
The first function you'll have to complete is init.
第一个要完成的函数是 init
This function takes as input a GPS position,
这个函数代入 GPS 位置
an initial heading estimate, and an array of uncertainties
初始航向预估 以及这些测量值的
for these measurements.
不确定性数列
It then should sample from a Gaussion distribution centered
然后 它从围绕这些测量值的
around these measurements to initialize all the particles.
高斯分布中取样 初始化所有粒子
It should also initialize all particle weights to 1.
它还会将所有粒子权重初始化为 1
You can look at the details for the particle_struct
你可以看一下 particle_struct 和
and particle_filter.h.
Particle_filter.h 的详情
The particle filter class has an internal structure
粒子滤波器类中 包括了
of particles that is updated.
更新后的粒子结构
So nothing is returned from this function.
因此 函数不会返回任何内容
The next function is prediction.
下一个函数是预测函数
This function takes as input the amount
它代入不同时间步之间的时间间隔
of time between time steps, the velocity and yaw rate
速度和角速度测量值的不确定性
measurement uncertainties, and the current time step velocity
以及当前时间步的
and yaw rate measurements.
速度和角速度测量值
Using these measurements, it should
然后 它利用这些测量值
update each particle's position estimates
更新每个粒子的位置估算
and account for sensor noise by adding Gaussian noise.
并添加高斯噪作为传感器噪
Once again, you can add Gaussian noise
同样地 你可以从高斯分布中取样
by sampling from a Gaussion distribution
从而添加高斯噪但该高斯分布
with mean equal to the updated particle position,
的均值必须等于更新的粒子位置
and standard deviation equal to the standard deviation
其标准偏差等于测量值的
of the measurements.
标准偏差
The data association function here
这里的数据关联函数
takes as input two vectors of landmark obs objects.
输入 LandmarkObs 对象的两个向量
You can find the definition for this struct
你可以在 helperfunctions.h 找到
in helperfunctions.h.
这个结构的定义
This first vector is the prediction measurements
第一个向量是某个特定粒子和处于
between one particular particle and all of the map
传感器范围内的所有地图地标之间的
landmarks within sensor range.
预测测量值
This other vector here is the actual landmark measurements
这里的另一个向量 是激光雷达的
gathered from the LIDAR.
实际地标测量值
This function will perform nearest neighbor data
这个函数会执行最近邻数据关联
association and assign each sensor observation
并为每个传感器观察的数据
the map landmark ID associated with it.
分配相关联的地图地标 ID
Next you'll need to complete the update weights function.
接下来 你需要完成更新权重函数
This function takes the range of the sensor,
这个函数代入传感器范围
the landmark measurement uncertainties,
地标测量值的不确定性
a vector of landmark measurements,
一个地标测量值向量
and the map landmarks as input.
以及地图地标
The first thing you'll need to do here
这里 你要做的第一件事
is to predict measurements to all the map
就是预测传感器范围内
landmarks within sensor range for each particle.
每个粒子到所有地图地标的距离
Once you have these predicted landmark measurements,
获得了这些预测的地标测量值后
you can use the data association function
你就可以使用已经实现的数据关联函数
you've implemented to associate the sensor measurements to map
把传感器测量值和地图地标
landmarks.
关联起来
You'll need these associations to calculate
你需要这些关联
the new weight of each particle by using
借助我们本课讨论过的
the multivariate Gaussian probability density function
高斯概率密度函数 来计算每个粒子的
we discussed in the lesson.
新权重
Finally, you'll have to normalize these weights so
最后 你需要对这些权重归一化处理
that they'll be in the range 0 to 1
将其范围转换为 0 到 1
because next you'll use these weights as probabilities
因为接下来 你需要使用这些权重
for resampling.
作为重采样的概率
You're almost there.
进度不错
The next function is the resample function.
下一函数是重采样函数
You can use the weights of the particles in your particle
你可以使用粒子滤波器中的粒子权重
filter and c++ standard libraries discrete distribution
以及 C++ 标准库的离散分布函数
function to update your particles to the Bayesian
把你的粒子更新为贝叶斯
posterior distribution.
后验分布
Finally, you're at the last step.
下面 最后一步
You'll evaluate your particle filter
你需要计算加权误差
by calculating the weighted error.
从而评估你的粒子滤波器
This function takes the ground truth position
这个代入某个特定时间步的
at a particular time step as input
地面真实位置
and calculates the weighted error of your particle filter
然后使用每个粒子的权重
using the weights of each particle.
计算出你的粒子滤波器的加权误差
Feel free to check out the files helperfunction.h,
如果你想更深入了解这段代码
map.h, and particlefilter.h if you're curious about the finer
可以自己查看 helperfunction.h、map.h、以及 particlefilter.h
details of the code.
文件
To build and run your code, open a terminal
要编写并运行你自己的代码 你需要打开终端
and simply go to the localization particle filter
打开定位粒子滤波器的主目录
home directory, then type build.sh
然后键入 build.sh
and then run.sh to run your particle filter.
接着键入 run.sh 运行你的粒子滤波器
Now I'm handing it over to you.
现在 我把时间交给你
You have all the tools you'll need to complete the particle
所有工具都已齐备 完成你的
filter project.
粒子滤波器项目吧
Have fun and see you on the other side.
祝你好运